Guide to the Nell Mondy papers, 1932-2005.
Mondy, Nell papers, 1932-2005
- X. Cornell
  - 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Potato Varieties (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Potato Varieties (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - South America Reminiscences, Undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Nell's introduction to the potato, Undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - South America Reminiscences, Undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Food, Chemistry and You by Nell, Undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Nell of Cornell, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Nutrition
    - Garza Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Division of Publication List, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Lock on Potato Rom, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Naming of Kinzelberg Hall, 1997-06-06 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Cornell Press
    - Elected Fellow American Institute of Chemists, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Featured in the World Who's Who of Women, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Birkett Williams Lecture Ouchita Baptist University, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Mondy promoted to Full Professor, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Elected Fellow American Association for Advanced Science, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - News Release from IFT (Research in Journal of Food Science), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Elected President Graduate Women in Science, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Honorary Life Member in Potato Association of America, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Elected Fellow of Institute Food Technologists, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - National Honorary Member Graduate Women in Science, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Membership in Graduate Fields at Cornell
    - Food Science (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Toxicology (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Nutritional Science (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cornell Presidents
    - President Day (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - President Malott (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - President Perkins (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - President Rhodes (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Landlords Association of Tompkins County, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Landlords Association of Tompkins County, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Landlords Association of Tompkins County, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Landlords Association of Tompkins County, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Cornell Housing, 1960-1979 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Cornell Speeches - Women's Issues (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Committees- Cornell Faculty, 1954-1990 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Ithaca Weather (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Cornellian (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Brief History of Activities since appointment at Cornell, 1945-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Institute of Toxicology
    - Origins (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Faculty (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Students (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Publications (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Proposal, 1979-09 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - ICET Symposium, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Wilkinson Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - ICET News (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Toxic 1982-1987 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Center for Environment (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Development of Program-Training, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Catalog Description of Toxicology (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Institute of Food Science
    - Origin of Institute of Food Science, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Washington Meeting on Food Science, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Committee on Course Study, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Food Science Policy Subcommittee I, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Food Science Policy Subcommittee II, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - FS Policy Committee, ad hoc Committee Report, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Proposal for Establishment of Single Department of Food Science, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Dean Barns' Proposal to Dean of Agriculture, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Distinguished Lecture Series Committee, Institute of Food Science and Marketing, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Newsletter, 1975, 1978, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Strategic Plan, Members Minutes, Advisory Council, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Contributions to IFS Newsletters, 1971-1978 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - World Food Congresses
    - International Congress, Glasgow, Scotland, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - 2nd International Congress of Food Science and Technology: Invitation and Visa, Poland, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Personal Correspondence: 2nd International Congress, Poland, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Map, Hotel, Travel (Poland), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Experience (Poland), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Map and Guide, Cards (Poland), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Polish Cookbook, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Russian Magazine, Train from Warsaw to Prague (Poland), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Third World Congress Food Science, Washington D.C., 1970 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - 2nd World Congress-Maps, Books, Magazines (Spain), 1987 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - 2nd World Congress of Food Technology Program, Barcelona, Spain, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Program Registrants: Fifth International Congress of Food Science and Technology (Japan), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Professional Cards, Fifth Congress (Japan), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Fifth Congress Abstract and Speech (Japan), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Fifth Congress Correspondence (Japan), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Nihon Kaken Co., Ltd. and S and B Shokuhin Co., Ltd. Correspondence (Japan), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Food Co. and Osaka Women University Correspondence(Japan), 1979-1981 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - 6th World Congress, Ireland, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - 7th World Congress Food Science and Technology, Singapore, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - 8th World Congress, Toronto, Canada, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - 12th World Congress, Chicago, USA, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 56)
- XI. Correspondence
  - War Letters to Dr. Mondy, 1944-1950 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence - Dean Elizabeth Vincent, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence - Hazel Hauck, 1952-1959 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence - Faith Fenton, 1955-1978 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Finland, 1958-1988 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence - Undergraduates, 1959-1998 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence - Betty Watts, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence - Catherine Personius, 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Sweden, 1960-1970 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Europe visit, 1961-1978 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Norway, 1962-1972 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence - Graduate Students, 1962-1994 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Korea, 1965-1990 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1966-1994 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Poland, 1966-1985 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Christmas Letters, 1966-2004 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Industry Letters, 1966-1996 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Faculty Letters, 1966-1996 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - "The Dark Age" - Correspondence, 1966-1978 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence - R.T. French Company, 1967-1974 (Box 20, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence - Students, 1970-1989 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence - Students, 1970-1989 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - GWIS, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence - President of Ouachita Baptist University - Ben Elrod, 1974-1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Ruth Leverton Stiebling, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Correspondence - Mal Nesheim, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Japan, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence - Norm Childers, University of Florida, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence - Mal Nesheim, 1980-1995 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence - Maria Leja, post-doc, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence - Jeanette McCay, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - China, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - Soviet Union, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - Soviet Union and the Institute of Food Industry, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 61)
  - Philippines, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence - Louise Daniels, 1987-2001 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence - Marguerite Palmer, 1987-1996 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence - Dr.Sharada, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence - Dr. Kalpana Kulshrestha, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - Retirement Letters, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Ouachita Faculty Letters at Nell Mondy's retirement, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Taiwan, 1993-1996 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - Peru, Undated (Box 20, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence - Jack Bulloff, 1994-1997 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Myrtle Ericson, 1996-2002 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - General Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1940-1959 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Food Science Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Diaries (Box 18)
  - World War II Correspondence
    - Edith Chu, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Bill Daily, V-12 letters, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Dr. Grant, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 61>)
    - Thomas Gray, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Royal C. Gilkey, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Hy Kihara, 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Erwin Kelley, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Pat Moseley, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Jack Vestal, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Raldon Wiles, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Mondy's Correspondence with fans, 1980-1989 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Mondy's Correspondence with fans, 1990-1993 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Mondy's Correspondence with fans, 1994-2000 (Box 12, Folder 84)
- XII. Subject Files
  - Birkett Williams Lecture (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Notebook from Dr. Sumner's enzyme course (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Long Vita (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lipid/Virus Project (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Theses (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - 1965 Centennial (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Nobel Prize for Dr. Sumner (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Frontiers in Food Science (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Hotel School (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Florida State University - leave from Cornell, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Faculty Salaries (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - AVI- Publishing Company (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Book (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Book and AVI (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Reflections of Trips to Korea, Japan and Indonesia (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Dr. James Sumner - Biographical Information (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Nell Mondy's Notebook in Dr. James Sumner's Last Course on Enzymes, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Copy of Dr. James Sumner Book "Laboratory Experiments in Biological Chemistry", 1944 (Box 10)
  - World War II
    - World War II, Casualties (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - World War II, relics (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - War letters- Ouachita (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Korean War
    - John Skory, Korean War, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Women
    - Women Scientists Problems and Prospects-Rossi (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Women Scientists in America-Rossiter (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Committees for Women of Assoc. of Scientists (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - The Double Bind: The Price of Being a Woman and a Minority Woman in Science- Shirley Malcom (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Women in Science (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Cornell 11 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Washington's Women Network (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Washington Women Directory (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - National Security Institute for Women (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - Women and Minorities in Science and Engineering (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Women Equality Day (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Cornell Women - Research (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - Women's Studies at Cornell (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Dr. Viola Graham - Copy of her will and biographical piece (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Dr. Viola Graham - Correspondence concerning Sigma Delta Epsilon and the Award for Excellence, 1973-1983 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Dr. Viola Graham - Nomination Women's Hall of Fame, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Requests
    - Examples of Persons and Places (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Telephone Requests, 1986-1992 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Examples of Reprint Requests According to Country (Box 11, Folder 116)
    - Examples of Reprints According to Request by Number (Box 11, Folder 117)
    - Example of Mondy's Publications by Number (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Reviews
    - Mondy Review of Oregon State Project, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - Mondy Examples of Reviews of Manuscripts for Journals (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Mondy Review for USDA Value Added Products (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - Example of Projects Reviewed by Mondy for Funding (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Dr. Marion Pfund, Emeritus Professor
    - General Information (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Salary (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Professor Emerita, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, Clippings, Vitae, 1953-1997 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1994 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Photographs of Pfund, 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Marion Pfund's copies of her "Chemistry and Food Preparation" Manuals, 1946; 1951 (Box 10)
  - Crime Report
    - Chronology of the Crime (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ithaca Journal Clippings Concerning the Crime (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Police Photos of Mondy's Damages, 1996-02 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Grand Jury Hearing (Assistant DA Flash), 1996-03-13 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Order of Protection - Larkin, 1996-02-29 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Order of Protection - Sherman, 1996-03-14;1996-08-14 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Cornell Police - Safety suggestions for Home (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Pretrial Crime Clippings, 1996-03-1996-06 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Clippings of other Crimes in Ithaca Area (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Clippings of Activities following the crime (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mondy's Letters to Ithaca Journal, 1996-2002 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Mondy's Medical Bills and Letters from Physician (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Drugs, Crime, and Yellow Butterflies" Mondy's Reflection on the Court Hearings and Role of Officers (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Crime Victims Bill of Rights (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Community Forum, 1996-08-26 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Crime Victim's Needs as Summarized by Mondy (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Letters to Judge Sherman (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Court-Victim's Statement, 1996-08-12 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Judge Sherman's Sentencing Order, 1996-08-11 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Ithaca Journal Announcing Sentence, 1996-08-13 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Parole Regulations (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - District Attorney Letter on Probation (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Some District Attorney Reports to Mondy (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Second Hearing on Restitution, 1996-09-27 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Second Hearing on Restitution, 1996-09-27 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Tompkins County Jail Regulations (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Chronology of Restitution (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Chronology of Restitution (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Chronology of Restitution (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Mondy's Speeches and Promotion of Community Activities (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Victim's Rights Week, 1997-04-13-1997-04-19 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Local Publicity WHCU and TV Channel 7 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Assistance on Victim's Organization from Westchester County, New York (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Chronology of Clippings on Crime (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Ithaca's Establishment of a Public Safety Committee, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Mondy Serves 1996 and Elected 1999 to the Criminal Justice Advisory Board (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Meetings of Criminal Justice Advisory Board, 1996, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Meetings of Criminal Justice Advisory Board, 1996, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Meetings - Criminal Justice Advisory Board, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Letters of Commendation from CJAB Chairman, 2002-09-30 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Victim's Sub-committee Membership (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Victim's Sub-committee meetings, 1996-2000 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Meetings of Sub-Committee, 1977-1990 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Meetings of Sub-Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Activities of Crime Victim's Sub-Committee - Mondy's Report (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Crime Victim's Services in General (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Hire for Two New Positions in Victim's Services (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - New York State Crime Victim's Board (CVB) (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Crime Victim's Board, 1993-1997 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Crime Victim's Board Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Victim's Assistance Program attempts to obtain Mondy's Restitution (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Crime Victim's Board, 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Letters to and from Crime Victim's Board, 1996-03-1999-10 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - DA Recommends Mondy for Crime Victim's Board Advisory Council, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - TRIAD & Ithaca Journal Report - Seniors Join Police, 1997-04-27 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Victim's Rights Amendment: Proposal to Amend US Constitution (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Balancing Justice in New York State, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Community Justice Center and Dispute Resolution Center (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Restorative Justice How a Bill becomes a Law (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - Restorative Justice Concepts (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - Restorative Justice Meetings, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - Restorative Justice Meetings, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Martin Luster Assemblyman 128th District (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - Senator James Seward 50th State District (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - Joseph Bruno - Majority Leader New York Senate (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - Sheldon Silver - Speaker of New York Assembly (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Governor George Pataki (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Attorney General Vacco (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Senator Volker - Chair Codes Committee Senate (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - BJ Appeal First Notice, 1997-12 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - DA's Response to Appeal - Sent to Appellate Division, 1998-12 (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Arguing the Appeal in Albany, 1999-02-09 (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Appellate Division Decision in Response to Appeal, 1999-03 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - Appellate Decision (Favorable to DA), 1999-03-1999-11-15 (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Assembly - Law 4302 (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - Senate Bill 458 Introduced by Senator Larkin (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Different Crime Laws (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - Support of DA for County Judge, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - Support of Dresser for Sheriff, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Support of Luster for reelection to Assembly, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 81)
- XIII. Ephemera
  - Pins (Box 17)
  - Donations to the Costume Collection, 1994-1999 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Carved key for Sigma Delta Epsilon, by Dr. Vioila Graham, Date unknown (Folder 1)
- XIV. Videos, Tape Recordings, Photographs
  - Potato Research, 1989-06-10; VHS V-9216 (Box 19)
  - Dr. Nell Mondy Lecture at North Central Forest Experiment Station, 1987-06-23; VHS V-9217 (Box 19)
  - Lab, VHS V-9218 (Box 19)
  - Cooking in New York State; Spud Story and Interview with Dr. Neil [sic] Mondy, 1995-02-12; VHS V-9219 (Box 19)
  - Mann Library Addition: Nell Mondy / 1st Electron Microscope Photo of a Potato, 2003-10-31; VHS V-9220 (Box 19)
  - CNN, VHS V-9221 (Box 19)
  - Potatoes, VHS V-9222 (Box 19)
  - Nell's Lab and BLSP Method, VHS V-9223 (Box 19)
  - CNN, VHS V-9224 (Box 19)
  - Nell: Channel 7 News, 2001-04-25; VHS V-9225 (Box 19)
  - Black Spot, VHS V-9226 (Box 19)
  - Tape Recordings
    - Various topics, Undated; TR 16584-16614 (Box 22)
  - Photographs
    - Family, 1920-1929 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Family, 1900-1994 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      includes slides
    - Family, 1900-1939 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Male friends, 1940-1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Nell and her Mother, 1940-1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Portraits of Nell (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
    - Nell, 1940-1959 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Ouachita Baptist University, 1939-1943 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Texas, 1943-1944 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Associated Colleges of Upper New York, Sampson College, 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Family and friends, 1950-1969 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Friends, 1950-1969 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Institute of Food Technologists, 1960-1969 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Nell, 1960-1979 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Nell, 1960-1979 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Nell and friends, 1960-1989 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Friends, 1960-1989 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - International visitors, 1960-1999 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Graduate Women in Science, 1980-1989 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Nell, 1980-1989 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Nell with friends, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Friends, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Nell with friends, 1989-2003 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Nell with friends, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Symposium on Food Science and Technology, 1987, 1989, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Nell with friends, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Nell, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Nell in her office and at home, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Home on Honness, 1990-2002 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Nell's retirement, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Nell receiving IFT Award, 19697 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Nell wtith friends, 1997-2004 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Nell's 75th birthday party, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Display in MVR Hall of Nell, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - College of Agriculture Outstanding Alumni Award, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Office in MVR Hall and dedication of Lab for Human Performance, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Dedication of Lab for Human Performance, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Nell at Pocahontas, Arkansas High School, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Ithaca, 1900, 1950-1979 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Japan and Seoul, 1970-1979 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Australia, Bolivia, Chili, China, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - India, Indonesia, Ireland, Ivory Coast, 1980-1999 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Taiwan, Thailand, 1980-1989 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Nigeria, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - New Zeland and Nigeria, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Peru, Philippines, Poland, Russia, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Scotland, Singapore, Switzerland, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - African Potato Association, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 48)